Welcome to this video about the
environment transfers feature.
Transferring environments between
different Entra tenants can now be done
through the tenant admin center.
Customers can use this feature when
they're consolidating multiple tenants
into one. For example, when
organizations are merging with one
another or acquiring each other.
Additionally, partners can use this
feature if they prepare demo
environments in their own tenant, which
they can then transfer to prospective
customers for evaluation or testing.
Let's go straight to the demo.
To transfer an environment,
we open the tenant admin center of the
source Entra tenant,
and click on the new action button at
the top of the screen called environment
transfers.
We then select the option transfer
environments,
and from this flyout we can select one
or more environments that we wish to
transfer to the same Microsoft Entra
tenant.
Then we must specify the
the Microsoft tenant ID of the
destination tenant to which we want to
transfer this environments.
We have the option to select when we
want the transfer to execute.
The transfer can run at most 2 weeks
into the future.
Let's select, for example, to run in 1
week from now
at 3:00 p.m.
Once we have the parameters selected,
then we click on transfer.
If we click again on the environment
transfer action,
we should see the pending outgoing
transfers from the flyout.
The source tenant also has the option to
cancel pending outgoing transfers by
clicking on the checkbox
and selecting the cancel transfers
button.
It is also possible to verify that the
transfer has been requested by going to
the environment operations page of the
source tenant admin center.
Here we see a list of environment
operations and we can see
a transfer request in queue status.
Here we can see all the operation
details such as the destination tenant
ID who is to receive the environment
and when the environment is expected to
run.
The second step for transferring an
environment is to accept
the transfer request from the
destination tenant.
For this we open the tenant admin center
from the destination tenant who is to
receive the environments.
To receive the environments we click
again on the action called
environment transfers.
And we select the option receive
environments.
Then we must specify
the source Microsoft Azure tenant ID
from which we are expecting the
environments to come.
Then we click next.
And we should see a list of pending
incoming transfers.
All the incoming transfers are selected
by default
but can be selected at your discretion.
Select the environment transfers that
you want to receive
and click on confirm.
If you want to verify that you have
accepted the environment transfer
you click again on the environment
transfers action
select receive environments
once again specify the source and your
tenant ID.
And then you can see
the list of accepted incoming transfers
and the time at which they are expected
to execute.
Here are some things that are good to
know. Environment transfers can only be
requested and accepted by internal
administrators.
Once a transfer has been started from
the source tenant,
the request has to be accepted by the
destination tenant within 8 hours.
The source tenant can schedule a
transfer
up to 14 days in the future.
Additionally,
the destination tenant must have a paid
Business Central license and should
ensure to have available environment
quota.
Finally, the transfer operation is
auditable in both tenants and in
environment telemetry.
If you want to learn more, make sure to
visit our Business Central resources,
including our documentation, Yammer, and
more.
Thank you for watching.